Share

Privacy Policy
==============

Songwhip privacy policy

Effective date: 04 December 2020

Wilson Page Ltd. (“Songwhip”, “we”, “us” and “our”) is highly committed to protecting your personal information and your right to privacy. If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or our practices with regards to your personal information, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://songwhip.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

When you visit our website https://songwhip.com (the "Website"), and more generally, use any of our services (the "Services", which include the Website), we appreciate that you are trusting us with your personal information. We take your privacy very seriously. In this Privacy Policy, we seek to explain to you in the clearest way possible what information we collect, how we use it and what rights you have in relation to it. We hope you take some time to read through it carefully, as it is important. If there are any terms in this Privacy Policy that you do not agree with, please discontinue use of our Services immediately.

This Privacy Policy applies to all information collected through our Services (which, as described above, includes our Website), as well as, any related services, sales, marketing or events.

Please read this Privacy Policy (“Policy”) carefully as it will help you understand what we do with the information that we collect.

**1\. What Information Do We Collect?**
---------------------------------------

In Short:  We collect personal information that you provide to us.

We collect personal information that you voluntarily provide to us when you register on the Website, express an interest in obtaining information about us or our products and Services when you participate in activities on the Website or otherwise when you contact us.

The personal information that we collect depends on the context of your interactions with us and the Website, the choices you make and the products and features you use. The personal information we collect may include the following:

### **Information you have provided to us**

* Name
* Photo
* Email address
* Social media handles

All personal information that you provide to us must be true, complete and accurate, and you must notify us of any changes to such personal information.

### **Information automatically collected**

In Short:  Some information — such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address and/or browser and device characteristics — is collected automatically when you visit our Website.

We automatically collect certain information when you visit, use or navigate Songwhip. Such type of information does not reveal your specific identity (like your name or contact information) but may include

* IP address
* Time of visit
* Device name
* Referring URLs
* Content viewed
* Registration time
* Usage information
* Browser information
* Geographic location
* Language preferences

### **Information collected from other sources**

In Short: We may collect limited information from public databases, marketing partners, social media platforms, and other outside sources.

In order to enhance our ability to provide relevant marketing, offers and services to you and update our records, we may obtain information about you from other sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners, affiliate programs, data providers, social media platforms, as well as from other third parties. This information includes:

* Name
* Photo
* Biography
* Email address
* Custom profiles
* Social media URLs

If you interact with us on a social media platform using your social media account (e.g. Facebook or Twitter), we receive personal information about you such as your name, email address, and gender. Any personal information that we collect from your social media account depends on your social media account's privacy settings.

**2\. How Do We Use Your Information?**
---------------------------------------

In Short:  We process your information for purposes based on legitimate business interests, the fulfilment of our contract with you, compliance with our legal obligations, and/or your consent.

We use personal information collected via our Website for a variety of business purposes described below. We process your personal information for these purposes in reliance on our legitimate business interests, in order to enter into or perform a contract with you, with your consent, and/or for compliance with our legal obligations. We indicate the specific processing grounds we rely on next to each purpose listed below.

* To protect our Services
* To manage user accounts
* To respond to user inquiries
* To provide and maintain our Service
* To send administrative information to you
* To detect, prevent and address technical issues
* To facilitate the account creation and login process
* To understand how users are engaging with our Service
* For any other purposes, we have asked your consent for

**3\. Will Your Personal Information Be Shared With Anyone?**
-------------------------------------------------------------

In Short:  We only share information with your consent, to comply with laws, to provide you with services, to protect your rights, or to fulfil business obligations.

We may process or share your personal information that we hold based on the following basis:

* **Consent**

We may process your personal information if you have given us specific consent to use your personal information for a specific purpose.

* **Affiliates**

We may share your information with our affiliates, in which case we will require those affiliates to honour this Privacy Policy. Affiliates include our parent company and any subsidiaries, joint venture partners or other companies that we control or that are under common control with us.

* **Business Partners**

We may share your information with our business partners to offer you certain products, services or promotions.

* **Business Transfers**

We may share or transfer your information in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company.

* **Legal Obligations**

We may disclose your information where we are legally required to do so in order to comply with applicable law, governmental requests, a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal processes, such as in response to a court order or a subpoena (including in response to public authorities to meet national security or law enforcement requirements).

* **Legitimate Interests**

We may process your data when it is reasonably necessary to achieve our legitimate business interests.

* **Performance of a Contract**

Where we have entered into a contract with you, we may process your personal information to fulfil the terms of our contract.

**4\. Who Else Can Access Your Information?**
---------------------------------------------

In Short:  We only share information with the following third parties.

We only share and disclose your information with the following third parties. We have categorized each party so that you may easily understand the purpose of our information collection and processing practices. If we have processed your personal information based on your consent and you wish to revoke your consent, please contact us using the contact details provided below in section 13.

* **Invoice and Billing**

Stripe and Paypal

* **Retargeting Platforms**

Facebook Custom Audience

* **Web and Mobile Analytics**

Google Analytics and Hotjar

* **Affiliate Marketing Programs**

iTunes Affiliate and Amazon Affiliate

* **Website Performance Monitoring**

Sentry and Cloudflare

* **User Account Registration and Authentication**

Google Sign-In

**5\. Do We Use Cookies And Other Tracking Technologies?**
----------------------------------------------------------

In Short: We may use cookies and other tracking technologies to analyze customer behaviour, administer the website, track users’ movements, and to collect information about users.

We may use cookies and other tracking technologies (like web beacons and pixels) to analyze customer behaviour, administer the website, track users’ movements, and to collect information about users. This is done in order to personalize and enhance your experience with us.

A cookie is a tiny text file stored on your computer. Cookies store information that is used to help make sites work. Only we can access the cookies created by our website. You can control your cookies at the browser level. Choosing to disable cookies may hinder your use of certain functions.

### **We May Use Cookies For The Following Purposes:**

* **Necessary Cookies**

These cookies are required for you to be able to use some important features on our website, such as logging in. These cookies don’t collect any personal information.

* **Functionality Cookies**

These cookies provide functionality that makes using our service more convenient and makes providing more personalized features possible.

* **Analytics Cookies**

These cookies are used to track the use and performance of our website and services.

**6\. What Is Our Stance On Third-party Websites?**
---------------------------------------------------

In Short: We are not responsible for the safety of any information that you share with third-party providers who advertise, but are not affiliated with, our Website.

The Website may contain advertisements from third parties that are not affiliated with us and which may link to other websites, online services or mobile applications. We cannot guarantee the safety and privacy of data you provide to any third parties. Any data collected by third parties is not covered by this Policy. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of any third parties, including other websites, services or applications that may be linked to or from the Website. You should review the policies of such third parties and contact them directly to respond to your questions.

* **YouTube**

Songwhip uses YouTube API Services to find and link to related video content. By using Songwhip, users are agreeing to be bound by the [YouTube Terms of Service](https://www.youtube.com/t/terms) and the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

**7\. How Long Do We Keep Your Information?**
---------------------------------------------

In Short: We keep your information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Policy unless otherwise required by law.

We will only keep your personal information for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). No purpose in this Policy will require us keeping your personal information for longer than one (1) months past the termination of the user's account.

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize such information or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

**8\. How Do We Keep Your Information Safe?**
---------------------------------------------

In Short: We aim to protect your personal information through a system of organizational and technical security measures.

We have implemented appropriate technical and organizational security measures designed to protect the security of any personal information we process. However, despite our safeguards and efforts to secure your information, no electronic transmission over the Internet or information storage technology can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, so we cannot promise or guarantee that hackers, cybercriminals, or other unauthorized third parties will not be able to defeat our security, and improperly collect, access, steal, or modify your information. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, the transmission of personal information to and from our Website is at your own risk. You should only access the Website within a secure environment.

**9\. Do We Collect Information From Minors?**
----------------------------------------------

In Short: We do not knowingly collect information from or market to children under 18 years of age.

We do not knowingly solicit information from or market to children under 18 years of age. By using the Website, you represent that you are at least 18 or that you are the parent or guardian of such a minor and consent to such minor dependent’s use of the Website. If we learn that personal information from users less than 18 years of age has been collected, we will deactivate the account and take reasonable measures to promptly delete such information from our records. If you become aware of any information we may have collected from children under age 18, please see section 13 below.

**10\. What Are Your Privacy Rights?**
--------------------------------------

In Short: In some regions, such as the European Economic Area, you have rights that allow you greater access to and control over your personal information. You may review, change, or terminate your account at any time.

In some regions (like the European Economic Area), you have certain rights under applicable data protection laws. These may include the right:

(i) to request access and obtain a copy of your personal information

(ii) to request rectification or erasure

(iii) to restrict the processing of your personal information

(iv) if applicable, to data portability. In certain circumstances, you may also have the right to object to the processing of your personal information. To make such a request, please use the contact details provided below in section 13. We will consider and act upon any request in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

If we are relying on your consent to process your personal information, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note however that this will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before its withdrawal, nor will it affect the processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

If you are a resident in the European Economic Area and you believe we are unlawfully processing your personal information, you also have the right to complain to your local data protection supervisory authority. You can find their contact details here: http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index\_en.htm.

If you are a resident in Switzerland, the contact details for the data protection authorities are available here: https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home.html.

* **Account Information**

If you would at any time like to review or change the information in your account or terminate your account, you can: Contact us using the contact information provided below in section 13. Upon your request to terminate your account, we will deactivate or delete your account and information from our active databases. However, we may retain some information in our files to prevent fraud, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Use and/or comply with applicable legal requirements.

* **Cookies And Similar Technologies**

Most Web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies. If you choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features or services of our Website. To opt-out of interest-based advertising by advertisers on our Website visit http://www.aboutads.info/choices

* **Opting Out Of Email Marketing**

You can unsubscribe from our marketing email list at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the emails that we send or by contacting us using the details provided below. You will then be removed from the marketing email list — however, we may still communicate with you, for example, to send you service-related emails that are necessary for the administration and use of your account, to respond to service requests, or for other non-marketing purposes. To otherwise opt-out, you may: Contact us using the contact information provided below in section 13.

**11\. How Can You Review, Update, Or Delete The Data We Collect From You?**  
------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Based on the applicable laws of your country, you may have the right to request access to the personal information we collect from you, change that information, or delete it in some circumstances. To request to review, update, or delete your personal information, please see section 13 below. We will respond to your request within 30 days.

**12\. Do We Make Updates To This Policy?**
-------------------------------------------

In Short: Yes, we will update this Policy as necessary to stay compliant with relevant laws.

We may update this Policy from time to time. The updated version will be indicated by an updated "Effective" date and the updated version will be effective as soon as it is accessible. If we make material changes to this Policy, we may notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to review this Policy frequently to be informed of how we are protecting your information.

**13\. How Can You Contact Us About This Policy?**
--------------------------------------------------

If You have any questions or complaints about this Policy, please [contact us](https://songwhip.com/contact) electronically or send a physical mail to:  
  
Wilson Page Ltd.  
Telecom House,  
125-135 Preston Road,  
Brighton, United Kingdom, BN1 6AF  
Attention: Songwhip Legal

Top searches

Featured artists

© 2024 Songwhip · [Privacy](https://songwhip.com/privacy) & [Terms](https://songwhip.com/terms)

Login

© 2024 Songwhip • [Privacy](https://songwhip.com/privacy) & [Terms](https://songwhip.com/terms)
